Jeff Walker

"Not only working software, but also well-crafted software" —Manifesto for Software Craftsmanship

Software Craftsman

Twenty-two years of experience as a software developer and architect * Agile * Cloud * Design Patterns * Refactoring * Domain Driven Design (DDD) * Full-stack

"writes code as fast and as beautiful as any developer I've known." —Craig McKeachie

"very detail oriented and meticulous, consistently producing top-quality work." —Scott Walker

"one of the most talented developers that I've had the opportunity to work with."

—Keith Byers

Language Designer

AZOTH: Pivoted to working on Azoth, a language with reference capabilities and structured concurrency * Adapted Adamant language reference and compiler to Azoth * Migrated compiler to rewritable reference attributed grammar (ReRAG) approach with code generation * Experimented with nanopass approach

ADAMANT: Conceived and designed a new programming language * Wrote a compiler for a subset * Drafted a Language Reference * Created a VSCode extension for syntax highlighting * Researched language design including: Rust, Swift, C#, Scala, Project Midori, Java, Kotlin, Idris, Pony, Fortress, and JAI * Researched compiler construction tools & type systems for memory management

OTHER: Revised a Domain Specific Language (DSL) design for TDCI * Created a Scheme variant and interpreter for a college winter-term project

Portfolio

SemVer NuGet Package
Azoth Language Site
Azoth Compiler
ExhaustiveMatching.Analyzer
Adamant Lang. Site, Blog, & Docs
Adamant Compiler
Algorithm Comparison: Rust and C#
Software Development Blog
JavaScript Minefield (six post series)

Participative Tech. Leader

DEEPCELL: Technical lead and software architect of the instrument software team * Joined before Series A * Team started as myself and one junior developer * Hired until the team was myself, six developers, an SDET and a technical manager * Developed software for multiple generations of prototype instruments and the final REM-I instrument * Involved in all aspects of the instrument software including product design, UI, gathering requirements from internal users, and project management * Designed a framework for devices and device connections * Designed and implemented a framework for units of measurement * Designed and implemented a framework for safe concurrency in WPF and enabling structured concurrency * Designed and implemented framework for advanced time series data management and computation on the instrument * Code review * Mentorship * Set code conventions and set up tools to aid and enforce them

SCHOOLPOINTE: Head of all technical employees; reported directly to president * Managed four developers and a sysadmin working on three products serving 375+ school districts * Multiple successful hires * Created product design for Learning Management System (LMS) * Architect and lead developer of LMS, a hosted web app deployed to AWS * Learned and used DynamoDB * Oversaw improvements to architecture leading to increased uptime and reduced costs * Led push to consolidate code bases, putting the company in a stronger position to innovate * Oversaw start of transition to a DevOps approach including infrastructure as code and zero-downtime deployments

PRIMARY FINANCIAL COMPANY: Tech. lead of a six developer team * Software architect * Implemented an Agile methodology and a Domain Driven Design (DDD) approach * Collaborated with the customer to understand the domain and domain language * Designed the domain model * Performed all code reviews * Mentored junior team members

github.com/WalkerCodeRanger/semver azoth-lang.org github.com/azoth-lang/azoth.tools.bootstrap github.com/WalkerCodeRanger/ExhaustiveMatching adamant-lang.org blog.adamant-lang.org/archive github.com/adamant/adamant.tools.compiler.bootstrap github.com/WalkerCodeRanger/dfaMinimizationComparison WalkerCodeRanger.com/blog WalkerCodeRanger.com/blog/2014/02/javascript-minefield

Experience

Aug. 2019 - Mar. 2024	Deepcell	deepcell.com
Oct. 2020 - Present	Azoth Programming Language Independent Project	azoth-lang.org
May 2018 - Aug. 2020	Adamant Programming Language	adamant-lang.org
Feb. 2017 - Sept. 2018	Affinion Group Consultant via The Execu Search Group	execu-search.com
Feb. 2016 – Jan. 2017	Adamantworks/Sabbatical Started Adamantworks LLC	
Sept. 2013 - Jan. 2016	SchoolPointe	
Aug. 2012 - Sept. 2013	Apprisen Consultant via Quick Solutions	apprisen.com
May 2010 - Aug. 2012	Primary Financial Company Consultant via Quick Solutions	epfc.com
Apr. 2010	Resource Interactive Consultant via Information Control Corporation	
Oct. 2009 - Feb. 2010	Information Control Corporation	
Oct. 2008 - Aug. 2009	TDCI	
June-Oct. 2008	Chase Consultant via Quick Solutions	chase.com
Dec. 2007 - May 2008	United Healthcare Consultant via Oxford Consulting	uhc.com
July 2004 - Nov. 2007	Foresight Corporation Hired full-time Oct. 2004	
Aug. 2002 – June 2004	Optimum Technology	otech.com
Spring 2002	Advanced Topics in Object-Oriented Programming	
	ExCo (Experimental College) Instructor at Oberlin College	
	Received three credits for teaching an ExCo course at Oberlin College	

Publications

Sept. 2023 COSMOS: a platform for real-time morphology-based, label-free cell sorting using deep learning

(Preprint) Mar. 2022 Realtime morphological characterization and sorting of unlabeled viable cells using deep learning

Education

B.A. in Computer Science, Minor in Mathematics

May 2002 | OBERLIN COLLEGE

Core Skills

C# * Agile * Design Patterns * Refactoring * Domain Driven Design (DDD)

oberlin.edu

- * Domain Modeling * Software Architecture * Mentoring * Technical Leadership
- * Code Review * Instrument Software * Programming Language Design * Structured Concurrency * ASP.NET MVC * HTML * CSS * JavaScript * Management
- * Compilers * SQL * SQL Server * Hiring * Agile and Lean Project Management
- * Domain Specific Language (DSL) Design * Product Design

Experience With

Reactive Extensions (Rx.NET) * Reactive UI * async/await * Windows Presentation Foundation (WPF) * Test-Driven Development (TDD) * IoC Containers * Simple Injector * Pair Programming * NodaTime * Task-like types * Cloud Migration

- * Blue-green Deployment * Amazon Web Services (AWS) * S3 * DynamoDB
- * NHibernate * T4 Templates * Python * Roslyn Analyzers * UML * Scrum * Rust
- * Less * jQuery * XML * Parser Generators * Entrepreneurship * DevOps * XAML
- * SQL Azure * Azure Cloud * Azure Queues * Oracle Server * Behavior-Driven Development (BDD) * Publishing NuGet Packages * ASP.NET Forms * C/C++
- * Many more